Mateusz Dymiński

Mobile: +48 692-276-472

E-mail: <u>dyminski@gmail.com</u>

Address: Marca Polo 15/16, 50-504 Wrocław, Poland

Date of birth: 18/01/1988

Twitter @m_dyminski

GitHub https://github.com/mateuszdyminski



Professional summary:

Software developer with strong technical background in software development and scientific approach. 4+ years of experience in building large, distributed and highly-reliable enterprise software. Since the beginning of 2014 obsessed about the Golang. Currently focused on building reliable distributed systems for cloud environment. Interested in databases (Cassandra, InfluxDB), computing frameworks (Hadoop), messaging systems (Kafka), stream-processing (Storm), enterprise-scale monitoring tools (Graphite, InfluxDB, Librato, Sensu), search engines (ElasticSearch), continuous integration (Git, Jenkins, Cucumber) and continuous deployment (Ansible, Vagrant, Docker). Tolerate Javascript:) Clean code and functional programming enthusiast. Always excited about learning new things.

Skills Summary:

- Programming languages: Golang, Java, JavaScript
- Frameworks: Storm, Hadoop, ElasticSearch, Zookeeper, Etcd, Guice, Guava, RxJava
- Databases: Cassandra, Postgres, Redis, InfluxDB, RocksDB
- Continuous Integration + Deployment: Maven, Jenkins, Ansible, Graphite, Sensu, Librato
- Version Systems: GIT, SVN
- Tests: jUnit, Mockito, Selenium, Cucumber, TDD
- Web: HTML, CSS, AngularJS, WebSockets
- Messaging: KafkaIDE's: IntelliJ, Sublime
- Operating systems: Linux(Debian-based, CoreOS), Windows

All skills are arranged in order from most known.

Education:

• 2007 - 2011 Wroclaw University of Technology

Degree: BSc - Computer Science

• 2011 - 2013 Wroclaw University of Technology

Degree: MSc - Computer Science

 2011 – 2012 University of Novi Sad Erasmus Mundus Exchange Program

Employment History:

Siili Solutions

Senior Software Developer

August 2014 – present

Context:

We are building a high velocity, highly scalable micro-services based RESTful back-end. Share-nothing architecture and failover are always in our minds. Our team is also building a few front-end clients for this back-end, some browser based, some native mobile based.

Main duties:

- Designing the share-nothing architecture of the solution, implementation tasks within all layers
- Direct cooperation with the customer
- Focused on backend side of the project
- · Taking part in regular daily project duties

Technologies used:

Golang, REST, Java8, AngularJS, PostgreSQL, Kafka, Redis, AWS EC2, ElasticSearch, Librato

Nokia Networks

Lead Java Developer

September 2013 – August 2014

Context:

Distributed real-time stream-based computation system on top of Apache Storm. Project started in Silicon Valley, after proof of concept phase transferred to Poland. Main functionalities: received, analyse and store the data, taken from all base stations in customer's cellular network. System is designed to be scalable and high-available. Daily data transfer was around 10TB and 10 millions events per sec during peak.

Main duties:

- Designing cloud, distributed and highly-reliable architecture
- Developing software implementation tasks within all layers
- Administering project
- Development team work organization, tasks scheduling, software development process monitoring
- Cooperation with analysts, gathering requirements
- Production environment design and implementation (using many cloud services)

Technologies used:

Java, Python, Storm, Esper, Hadoop, Guice, Netty, Vert.x, Infinispan, Zookeeper, Kryo, Cassandra, Kafka, Backbone, Socket.IO, Ansible, Sensu, Selenium, Cucumber

Nokia's Networks Business

Java Developer

June 2012 – September 2013

Context:

Distributed enterprise system on top of WebSphere application server. System was designed to tracing-analyzing network elements in customer networks. Main functionalities: visualization of calls, report preparation, handling big amount of data.

Main duties:

- Designing the architecture of the solution, implementation tasks within all layers
- Direct cooperation with the architects of the base framework solution
- Taking part in regular daily project duties, bugs handling and processing

Technologies used:

Java SE + EE, EJB3, WebSphere, WebSphereMQ, Oracle, Swing, Robot

Hadapt

Big Data Developer Intern

November 2011 - March 2012

Context:

Hadapt has developed big data platform natively integrating SQL with Apache Hadoop. People who are behind Hadapt graduated at Wroclaw University of Technology so they started a series of courses for developers. I participated in first edition of this course.

Main duties:

- Data analysis using map-reduce paradigm on Hadoop platform
- Configuring clusters on Amazon EC2 platform
- Preparing data mining analysis with Apache Mahout
- Designing noSql schema in HBase database

Technologies used:

Java, Hadoop, Amazon AWS, Hbase, Mahout

PGS Software

C# Developer

January 2011 - October 2011

Context:

Employer is IT outsourcing company and I was assigned to StormDriver application. The inspiration for the project was StumbleUppon service. The main functionality was to aggregate the content from RSS feeds and create a recommendation engine which can serve interested websites for users. One of our main assumptions was to create a social portal where people could evaluate the proposed websites and create the 'viral' effect.

Main duties:

- Design and implementation tasks in all layers of the developed web application
- Taking part in regular daily project duties, bugs handling and processing

Technologies used:

C#, ASP.MVC2, Html, Css, jQuery, MS SQL Server

Other Qualifications:

English - C1 level (speaking, writing, listening, reading) - proficient

Drive license B